<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BOF on Yusuf Hegazy</title>
    <link>https://hegz.me/tags/bof/</link>
    <description>Recent content in BOF on Yusuf Hegazy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 19:07:42 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hegz.me/tags/bof/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Leaky Pipe</title>
      <link>https://hegz.me/writeups/leaky_pipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 19:07:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hegz.me/writeups/leaky_pipe/</guid>
      <description>In this challenge we recieved a binary in which we are asked to exploit and somehow retrieve the flag.
Initial Analysis We start by running the binary and checking it behavior.
./leaky_pipe We have just fixed the plumbing systm, let&#39;s hope there&#39;s no leaks! &amp;gt;.&amp;gt; aaaaah shiiit wtf is dat address doin here... 0x7ffde7760410 AAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAA &amp;lt;--- our input Segmentation fault (core dumped) And as we see, we can already get a segfault by spamming some A&amp;rsquo;s in the input.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trigger Happy (0xL4ugh CTF)</title>
      <link>https://hegz.me/writeups/trigger_happy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 16:33:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hegz.me/writeups/trigger_happy/</guid>
      <description>Some background This is a challenge from 0xl4ugh CTF which was inspired by RACTF&amp;rsquo;s not really ai challenge, It was the first ever pwn challenge I solve in a CTF alone and I really liked it hence I wanted to bring it to this CTF (you can even check my poorly written writeup for that challenge which I refuse to remove as It&amp;rsquo;s pretty awesome to look back and see how much did we grow).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buffer Overflows for Newbies</title>
      <link>https://hegz.me/posts/bof-for-normies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 02:46:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hegz.me/posts/bof-for-normies/</guid>
      <description>What is a Buffer anyway? We can think of buffers as containers to hold our data for later use, it&amp;rsquo;s not really something specific to computer science; In fact, we have buffers in electronics, mechanics, chemistry and even politics! We can say that the word buffer is just a fancy name for a placeholder (temporary storage)!
Buffer in Computer Science Now, it&amp;rsquo;s time to get more technical and get to know buffers more in computer science!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GDB Cheatsheet</title>
      <link>https://hegz.me/posts/gdb-cheatsheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 13:56:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hegz.me/posts/gdb-cheatsheet/</guid>
      <description>Data:
 disas main to disassemble function x/50wx $esp examine 50 words in hex starting from esp x/50i $eip examine 50 instructions from eip x anything examine address and show it’s contents info variables varname will show any variable address (for global!) info functions to list all functions info frame shows the saved RTN address under &amp;ldquo;saved eip&amp;rdquo; info proc map shows memory map ctx shows general info about everything (works in gef only)    Flow</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
